JACQUES DIAMBRA ODI

DATA SCIENTIST ♥ STONECREST, GA. UNITED STATES 6784090623

• DETAILS •

Stonecrest, Ga, United States 6784090623 jodiambra@gmail.com

o LINKS o

<u>Github</u>

<u>Portfolio</u>

<u>LinkedIn</u>

∘ SKILLS ∘

Python

SQL

Machine Learning

Exploratory Data Analysis

Tableau

Scikit-Learn

Pandas

Statistics

Plotly

Streamlit

Imputation

Time Series

Deep Learning

Deploying ML models

Computer Vision

KERAS/ Tensorflow

Logistic Regression

Linear Regression

KNN

Random Forest

Support Vector

CatBoost

XGBoost

Light GBM

PROFILE

Data Scientist

As a seasoned scientist, I have spent over 8 years working in a variety of research and development fields, always striving to gain a deeper understanding of the world around us. During this time, I have honed my skills in critical thinking, problemsolving, and data analysis, all of which have proven to be invaluable in my transition to the data science field. My passion for using data to uncover insights and drive decision-making led me to pursue a career in data science, where I can combine my scientific knowledge with advanced analytics techniques. With a strong foundation in statistics, programming, and machine learning, I can create models and algorithms that turn raw data into meaningful insights. I am eager to continue building my skills and applying them to real-world challenges.

★ PROJECTS

Spotify EDA and Web Application

December 2022 | Project

- Collaborated with software engineers to build a website for our project
- Led a team of 4 to conduct exploratory data analysis and statistical analysis on Spotify playlists, with interactive data visualizations
- Discovered popularity trends was correlated with music events and pop culture: music awards, fashion shows, movies, super bowl, festivals
- Demonstrated presentation skills with YouTube livestream

Megaline Plus

November 2022 | Web Notebook

- Used hypothesis testing to determine that the Ultimate plan brings in more revenue than the Surf plan
- Data suggested a marketing push towards the Surf plan would yield a higher cash on cash return
- Illustrated data usage to be the largest contributor to revenue
- Created a classification model to predict upgrade options for legacy plan holders, with 80% accuracy on an imbalanced dataset

Ice Retail

November 2022 | Web Notebook

- EDA on video game retail store sales
- Created interactive visualizations, identified patterns that lead to successful sales and other data driven insights
- Formulated business strategy for advertising campaign to maximize profit in regional markets

Sure Tomorrow Insurance

December 2022 | Web Notebook

- Applied machine learning and model tuning to identify similar customers
- Predicted whether a customer was likely to receive an insurance benefit
- Predicted the number of insurance benefits a customer was likely to receive
- Protected clients' personal data with obfuscation, without affecting model performance

Zyfra Gold Mining

November 2022 | Web Notebook

- Conducted EDA on gold refining process and removed outliers in data
- Illustrated the change in metal concentration through the purification process
- Tested models to predict gold recovery, ultimately choosing a decision tree

■ EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

QC Analyst | Arxada

December 2019

- Analyzed chemical, raw materials, in-process materials, or release test samples in support of compliance with company standards
- Interpreted and evaluated the analyses in terms of accuracy and precision compared against established specifications; recommended, and implemented corrective action where necessary
- Successfully took on the challenge of analyzing a 120% increase in lab samples
- Reduced the analysis time for HPLC azole method by 130%
- Team lead of 3 chemists

Research Associate | RCUOG

September 2016 — April 2019

- Teamed with 2 researchers in successfully identifying pro-inflammatory molecules involved in Areca nut carcinogenesis, using HPLC fractions (doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-18996-2)
- Contributed to leading-edge Areca nut carcinogenicity data; compiled, analyzed, and interpreted results leading to 1 publication, and Areca nut intervention studies with Guam Cancer Research Center
- Presented data to community at conferences and developed further studies and experimental designs to address similar research concerns

Research Lab Assistant | PITT Dept. Biological Sciences

 ${\it September 2011-April 2013}$

- Enhanced quantitative and qualitative analyses, such as sampling, testing, and measuring using specialized equipment, shaving 10% off analysis times
- Conducted DNA miniprep (purification) experiments with drosophila DNA with minimal supervision, followed experimental protocols

COURSES

Data Science Bootcamp, Practicum US

2022 — 2023

EDUCATION

M.S. Biology, University of Guam

August 2016 — April 2019

NIH/U54 Scholar

B.S. Biology, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh

August 2010 — April 2015